♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor ♪
["Mr. Tailor" playing]
- ♪ Fix it ♪
- ♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor ♪
♪ Holding the scissors ♪
♪ One cut, and it's over ♪
Act. Prove yourself.
I need the help
of the children of the thread.
- Emerson!
- [Cita] Emerson!
- [clanging]
- [gasping]
[Emerson] He said he needs our help.
Let's save him.
Olga is a scammer.
So, for sure, you're her fake daughter!
So does that mean…
I'm included,
because you called me? Right?
Maybe. You can be
Tape Measure, Pin Tape Measure.
[Audrey] The ambassador's bodyguard.
Samir?
I have a strong feeling…
he's the reason Atoy is missing.
[in English] I am very, very hungry.
[in English]  Can you--
[in English] Can you give me
some of that, please, sir?
[in English] I'm very, very hungry, sir.
[grunts, groans]
[Audrey] I can try to bump into him
to get information from him.
[in English] I want to find Atoy
just as much as you guys.
PREVIOUSLY
[Atoy, in English] Cufflinks.
We'll use this
in the first stage of our escape.
[gate lock rattling]
[Lily] Atoy, Atoy.
Here, here. Hold this,
hold this, hold this.
[Emerson] Tape Measure, Tape Measure,
I have a sighting of Tailor AFAM.
[in English] I already have visuals.
[in English] Be alert.
[Mongki] We can't spot Olga.
Some people say she jogs here often, but…
not even a shadow.
We also went to her house.
They said she already moved.
She's been gone a while.
Keeps moving around.
I'm sure she's hiding in Tabang Lupa.
Let's go.
[music fades]
Oh! Oh God!
[in English] Oh God! Oh God! Oh God!
[in English] Help! Oh God! Aw!
[in English] Help! Oh God! Oh God!
Help!
Aw! Aw! Aw!
[Emerson gasps in pain]
[in English] What happened? Are you okay?
[Emerson groans]
[in English] Yes, uh…
[in English] Um, uh, I have a--
[in English] I have, um… Uh…
Um, the pulikat! Pulikat.
[in English] What's pulikat in English?
Pulikat, pulikat.
- [in English] Kitty cat?
- [in English] Yes.
[in English] No! No, no, no, no!
[stammers] The…
[in English] The… The ouchy muscle!
[in English] Ouchy muscle. Ouchy muscle.
[in English] I have something for you.
- [in English] Ouchy muscle.
- [mutters]
[in English] This is for muscle.
[in English] Rub on your muscle, here.
- This is fine?
- Muscle-- Muscle soreness.
Ah, the--
[mumbles]
[in English] Okay, the-- [stutters]
[in English]  This one, huh.
- [in English] Just put it on your muscle.
- [in English] Okay, put it.
- [in English] Uh. Yes.
- Oh.
[in English] Over there. [titters]
You're kind, huh. It's just not obvious.
[in English] Uh, did you say something?
[in English] Uh, um, uh-- I mean…
[in English] You're a Good Samaritan
of the muscles.
Uh, thank you! Thank you.
You're welcome. You're welcome.
- Ah, yes! You…
- [indistinct]
[in English] You… You understand Tagalog?
- [in English] You can speak Tagalog?
- A little.
- Little.
- [in English] Just a little.
- [in English] Yes.
Oh, no.
- [groans]
- [in English] Okay.
[in English] Thread 1,
new location, confirm.
[grunts]
Um, uh, the…
[clears throat]
In the tree. [coughs]
[sneaky music playing]
Uh, th--th--th--
[clears throat]
Third tree. [coughs]
From the bridge! [coughs] From the bridge.
[in English] Roger that.
[in English] Did you say something again?
[in English] I'm, uh… No. I'm, uh…
I'm coughing. Uh, I'm coughing my pain.
- [in English] You feel better now?
- [in English] It's ouchy.
- [in English] You feel better, right? Yes.
- Feel a bit better.
[in English] Ouchy, ouchy! [coughs]
[clears throat, coughs]
[music fades]
[in English] Begin movement,
Adopted Thread.
Thread 1 confirmed the new location.
Three trees past the bridge.
Copy?
[in English] Copy, copy.
Auntie, ready?
[action music playing]
Let me just remind you of your mission.
[in English] Bump into Samir,
flirt, lure him into a date,
and find out where the Master Cutter is.
- [in English] Good job.
- [in English] Got it.
Good luck, Auntie.
[in English] Good luck, Mama Mary!
[music fades]
Go.
[suave theme music playing]
[in English] Uh, do you always jog here?
[in English] In this place, here. Yes?
Feeling close already.
Uh… [coughs]
[in English] Just my… my second time.
- [in English] Yes.
- [in English] Yes, yes.
- [in English] Me also, two times.
- [in English] Two time.
[in English] Two times, I come here.
But I like to explore, you know,
other places in the Philippines
and, uh, parks…
[in English] My mom and brother
are in the Philippines now.
[in English] Maybe you have
suggestions on where to go?
[in English] Suggestions. Other…
[sniffs] Um…
[in English] You know, at the…
[titters]
[in English] Nosebleed. Um, the…
[in English] Of all the places, maybe the…
- the Chocolate Beach in Bohol and the…
- [in English] Chocolate Beach.
the Boracay Hills.
- [in English] Okay.
- [in English] It's-- It's--
[in English] Uh, but it's… it's far.
[in English] If you want
to-to-to be nearby,
it's all-- Of all of the places, it's, uh…
Las, uh, Filipinas in Quezon City.
[in English] Yes. Very beautiful.
[in English] It's my favorite.
- [in English] Uh, very, uh, relaxing!
- [in English] Yeah.
[in English] Especially, uh…
Casa Monroy. The… Of all of the places.
- [in English] Uh, is it open at night?
- [in English] Yeah.
[in English] Yes. Open at night, yes. Uh…
Eh-- Uh, the…
[in English] There are
cultural dancers there.
The…
[in English] Cultural dancers!
[stammers, in English]
Interpretative dancing
is, uh, my favorite.
[in English] Of all of the places,
your family will, uh, will like it there.
- [in English] Oh, thank you. I--I--I think
- [in English] Of all the places.
maybe I'll bring my family there,
uh, maybe tonight.
[in English] Maybe, uh--
Eh, let's-let's see.
[in English] Maybe I'll bring
them there, yes?
[in English] Yes, maybe, maybe not.
Thank you. Thank you so much.
[in English] Okay-- Ha!
[giggles]
[in English] Okay, okay.
[suspicious music playing]
[in English] Excuse me.
[in English] Oh, okay.
[in English] We have news
about Dmitri Regalia.
[in English] What?
[in English] He is dead.
[in English] You'll go to the funeral.
[in English] Audrey and her daughter
will be at the funeral.
[Samir, in English] You bring them
back to me untouched.
[in English] Okay? We will use them
to extract information
from the prisoner.
[tense music playing]
- [Samir, in English] Bring them back.
- [in English] Mission abort.
[in English] Mission abort.
[Samir, in English]
Put them a in plastic container.
Wait, wait, Gavin.
[Audrey] Do you see Emerson?
What is he doing?
[in English] What does he mean by that?
- Eh, maybe…
- Huh?
he's imitating April Boy Regino?
Who? Who's that, Auntie?
Uh, the one who sang
"Di Ko Kayang Tanggapin."
[sneaky music playing]
Oh, look. He's signaling something else.
Why don't we have earpieces?
Only three are working, Auntie.
[in English] Choke?
Huh?
[in English] Uh-- One word, two syllables?
[in English] Short.
[Audrey, in English] Short--
- [in English] Child, child…
- Huh?
[in English] Um, come on. What else?
- [in English] Short, child…
- [in English] Kid?
[sneaky music playing]
[in English] Sleep.
Uh…
- [in English] Kid.
- [in English] Rest.
[in English] Nap?
- Huh?
- [in English] Kidnap.
- [in English] Kid-
- [in English] Kidnap?
- Auntie, he said kidnap!
- [in English] Kid-- Kidnap!
Oh, uh-- Oh, oh!
[in English] Uh, yes! My friend!
[in English] Uh, do you have
the-- the other, uh…
[in English] The cream for the…
- [in English] Where is that? The cream of…
- [in English] Yes, yes, yes, yes.
- [in English] Muscle pains. Yes.
- [in English] The cream-- Oh, yes.
- [in English] Yes. The muscle pain.
- [in English] Yes.
[in English] You know, my-my muscle
is, uh, is, uh,
- ouchy cagain. It's burning!
- [in English] Just put on the muscle.
[Emerson, in English] Uh, yes.
To the muscle.
Why is he saying that?
Is he telling us to leave?
Because maybe we'll get kidnapped?
Auntie, let's go. Let's go, Auntie!
- [Emerson] Is that it?
- [in English] Sir!
[in English] That's Audrey, right?
[squeals]
[in English] Oh, no, go.
Go, go, go, go, go!
[in English] Okay, uh--
[in English] No, no!
[Audrey, in English] Hurry, hurry.
[indistinct]
Tape Measure, Tape Measure.
Help Mama Mary and Adopted Thread.
They're being chased!
Go to them. Move now!
What? Wait, hold on.
I thought it was just a date.
Why do they want to kidnap them?
What happened?
I don't know. I don't know.
My muscle already hurts.
Just go to them!
I can't follow. I can't move.
[groans]
Okay. All right, all right. Roger.
[music swells]
Hey. Thread 3, Thread 3!
[in English] Do you copy?
Tailor AFAM is chasing
Mama Mary and Adopted Thread!
Follow them, Thread 3!
[in English] Do you copy?!
Thread 3!
[music fades]
Hello? Hello, Thread 1?
[in English] Do you read me?
We're already in position,
with Mini Thread.
[in English] Hello? Any instructions?
Hello, Thread 1? [clicks tongue]
[sighs] We're so bored here.
Feels like we're not doing anything.
We've already eaten so many banana cues!
[sighs]
Hello? Hello, Thread-- [clicks tongue]
[in English] I can't reach anyone, Ame.
[grunts]
[sighs]
[Kurt] We're blind here.
- [device blips]
- Uh.
Uh. [laughs]
Low battery.
[laughs]
That's why they can't hear me.
- [laughs]
- That's why.
Eh, maybe the mission is done.
- Mm-hmm.
- Maybe the operation is okay.
Should we go home?
[Kurt] Oh, wish we all could.
Oh.
[rousing music playing]
[tense music playing]
Uh. That's them, right?
[Kurt, in English] Wow! They're dedicated.
Why are they running so fast?
I thought it was just jogging?
- Oh, wait.
- Why does it look like they're chasing--
Yes.
Uh, I think I know that guy.
Uh, that's him!
The-- The ambassador's bodyguard. That's…
Samir!
That's Samir!
[in English] He's chasing Mama Mary
and Adopted Thread!
- Uh--
- Oh.
You're clueless.
Are you still clueless?
Is that Audrey?!
- Wait, wait, wait. Auntie, Auntie.
- [panting]
We need to get off the track,
so they won't follow us.
[in English] Okay, yes. Let's go!
That's them, boss.
Wow.
They still managed to stroll around.
Let's go. We need to get them.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
Your payment!
[in English] Here, here, here.
- [thuds]
- [groans]
[Gavin] Auntie!
[groans]
Auntie, sorry, but you need to get up.
They might catch us.
[foreboding music playing]
[in English] Come on.
Auntie, let's go.
[Gavin, in English] I got you, I got you.
- Let's go.
- [gasps]
- [in English] Here.
- [in English] Okay.
- [Gavin] Here, here.
- [whimpering]
- [grunts]
- [gasps]
[groans]
[Samir, in English] Where do you think
you are going?
[in English] Both of you
come with me. Right now!
[tense music playing]
[in English] You think that you
can protect her from me?!
[in English] You want to be a hero.
[ominous music playing]
[in English] Who else
wants to be a hero? Anyone?!
[gun cocks]
Go to hell!
[in English] Nobody leaves. All of you!
[in English] Drop your gun,
or there will be blood.
Who are you trying to scare, huh?
Hey, Blondie! Your payment!
You think you can escape from me?!
Later, Fatty!
You know I'm busy here, right?!
[grunting]
[action music playing]
Where are they?
They passed here, but they ran fast.
Actually, Ame, stay here.
[in English] I'll go look for them.
Hey, bro!
There's a royal rumble there.
AFAM versus blond thug
versus fat vendor with a bolo!
Huh? Where?
[Kurt] Hey, guys!
How are you?
Question.
In that rumble,
was there a sexy woman there?
[in English] Do you recall seeing one?
Yes!
She looked like Mama Mary.
And she was with a handsome young man.
[mid-tempo rock music playing]
Wait, uh--
[grunting and groaning]
[Audrey screams] Gavin! Gavin!
[in English] Be careful!
[grunts and groans]
Gavin! Gavin!
[in English] Let him go! Gavin!
[grunts]
[grunting and groaning]
[in English] Guys, let's go.
[Kurt] Mama Mary!
Children of the thread, let's go!
- Come on, come on.
- [in English] Let's go!
[grunting and groaning]
[in English] Sir, they're gone!
[music fades]
- [in English] They're gone.
- [in English] Let's go! Let's go.
Hey! Come back here! We're not done!
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey! Your payment!
[grunts]
[in English] Oh! Keep the change!
Move your ass!
[rousing music playing]
I don't know what to do with you anymore!
[Cita] Good thing no one got hurt!
Instead of just thinking about Atoy,
you made things worse!
Sorry, Miss Cita.
My God!
That was the only way
we thought we could help Atoy.
We didn't know
that would happen.
[Ame] It was Emerson.
You're the one
who planned everything, right?
Oh, come on, Ame.
Stop with the blaming!
We all just wanted to save Atoy.
I spoke to Atoy in my dream.
[in English] I had the purpose, you know?
So much happened.
We didn't expect Samir to chase us.
And then, Daddy's men were also there.
So, two groups were chasing us.
My God. Good thing you escaped!
But you shouldn't have brought Audrey!
She has a child waiting for her!
What if she got hurt?!
What about the child?!
Where is Audrey?
She's in the room, Mom.
She's resting, with Janine.
But guys, it wasn't for nothing.
Because I overheard Samir
and his companion.
Their plan is to kidnap Mama Mary.
Oh, Audrey.
So, they want to kidnap her
to blackmail Atoy.
So, what does that mean? They have Atoy.
- [Emerson] Oh.
- So, how would we know
where Brother Atoy is now?
What if we kidnap Samir?
- What?!
- Why?
Is he the only one who can kidnap?
We can too.
Look.
If we kidnap Samir,
we'll interrogate him.
We'll put him under that swinging light.
Like that.
We'll make him confess
where he brought Atoy.
[in English] What do you think?
But how will we do that?
We don't even know
where on earth that man is.
[action music playing]
[in English] Of all the places--
Maybe the,
the…
- the Chocolate Beach in Bohol and the…
- [in English] Chocolate Beach.
the Boracay Hills.
- [in English] Okay.
- [stammers, in English] It's-- But it's…
[in English] It's far.
[in English] If you want
to-to-to be nearby,
it's all-- Of all of the places, it's, uh…
Las, uh, Filipinas in Quezon City.
[in English] Yes. Very beautiful.
It's my favorite.
Uh, very, uh…
relaxing!
Especially, uh…
[in English] Casa Monroy. The…
Of all of the places.
Hmm.
I'll handle it.
I know his schedule tomorrow.
[mid-tempo rock music playing]
Enough.
Don't continue with your plans,
and you can't be involved in any mission
if you can't carry it out!
I'll do it.
I'll be the one to save Agent Padua.
Wait a minute, Uno!
You're not the only one
capable of finding a way.
Even if Miss Siony's fence
is taller than me,
I can still help.
[Cita] Wait, wait.
That's right!
Let's leave it to Uno.
He's more trained for missions like this!
What chance do we have
against Atoy's enemies?!
Mom, I can't just wait
for Brother Atoy to be saved.
I feel useless here.
And Uno,
you can't take deprive us
the chance to act too.
We love Brother Atoy,
so, we'll fight as well.
We had miscommunication earlier.
It's true.
And our coordination was weak.
[in English] But we can do better.
[in English] I think, with
a little planning and a little strategy,
we can still save Atoy.
[in English] And I believe
in what we're doing, so…
I'm still joining.
And just because you're good at combat
doesn't mean you alone decide
who helps and who doesn't.
This isn't the time to show off.
I'm not showing off.
[somber music playing]
All I mean, Gavin,
is I don't want anyone to get hurt!
We failed earlier.
And Miss Cita is worried!
Right?
Our enemies earlier…
We struggled to escape from them!
This isn't a joke!
So, let me do it.
Leave it to me. I can handle it.
[Emerson clears throat]
You know, Uno…
it's not just courage that's needed.
There must also be teamwork.
It's like thread, right?
If it's just one strand…
it's easy to break.
But if one strand
is added with another and another
and another and another and another… Mmm.
Right?
It becomes a bundle.
[pensive music playing]
It can't be broken anymore
because it's stronger and tougher.
That's how we should be in our mission.
We must be together.
I already know
where we can find Samir tomorrow night.
He'll be with innocent people,
so we can't just kidnap him there.
We need to be in disguise,
so we can smoothly take him
without anyone else harmed.
Oh, I'm joining that.
I don't want to wait alone again.
- Karla.
- [Karla] I don't want to wait alone.
We're complete now,
the children of the thread.
So, shall we?
[mid-tempo rock music playing]
Let's save Atoy!
[in English] Okay!
- [in English] Yes! Let's do this, guys!
- [in English] Let's go!
[in English] We do it right this time.
For Atoy.
- [in English] Okay!
- [Karla] That's it!
[in English] Let's go! Let's do this!
[in English] OKA. Operation Kidnap AFAM.
[in English] Let's go! Let's go!
Let's go, children of the thread!
Children of the thread!
- Fight! Let's go!
- [Karla, in English] Let's go.
[in English] So,
this is what we're gonna do.
[in English] Listen to me, listen to me,
listen to me. Okay.
Listen.
[groans]
[pensive music playing]
I'll teach you how to open it.
[Atoy] This will be quick.
So, insert what I gave you.
Then put it into the hole.
About halfway only.
Then turn it
about 30 degrees to the right.
[in English] What are you talking about?
[in English] Oh, we…
[in English] We miss our family.
[in English] Yes. We talk about love.
[Atoy] Then, Lily,
there's a button on the left.
Once you've turned it…
[Atoy sighs]
…match it with the click.
Then you'll hear…
- [sighs]
- [clicks]
There. I removed it.
I removed it.
- [suspicious music playing]
- [gate rattles]
[Atoy groans]
[henchman 2] You two, eat now.
You'll surely like this.
[Lily] I'll eat later.
I'll save that for later.
[henchman 2, in English] Is he dead?
[henchman 1, in English]
No. Very weak and stinky.
[doo slams shut]
[music fades]
Atoy, Atoy, they're gone.
[tense music playing]
All right.
[Lily] You should eat, Atoy.
You haven't eaten yet.
I'm fine. Don't mind me.
After you eat,
don't throw away the bone.
We can still use it.
Okay, but… I can't be the only one eating.
You should eat too. You need strength.
[speaks softly] Okay.
[music swells]
[music fades]
[electronic blipping]
[intense music playing]
- [grunts]
- [henchman 1, in English] You eat!
[Lily mumbles]
[bone swishes]
‪UP NEXT
- [bone swishes]
- [grunts]
So, how's it going? Have you found
the location of Tailor AFAM?
[Emerson] Update me
once you've found him, okay.
- [in English] Copy.
- [in English] Okay.
[in English] Roger that.
[in English] Yes, ma'am!
[in English] Okay. One, two, three, smile.
[in English] You're so cute.
[Kurt, in English] Thank you
so much. Oh! Sorry!
[in English] You look familiar.
[henchman 2] Is this
what you're looking for?
Raise your hands, or I'll shoot you!
["Mr. Tailor" playing]
- [grunts & gunshot]
- ♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor ♪
♪ Holding the scissors ♪
♪ One cut, and it's over ♪
♪ Fix it ♪
Subtitle translation by: Rachel C. Arias